A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, RG 5 Program Files, Subgroup Grant Files FA1795
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Arts and Culture, 1987-2016; 1; 28.1 Cubic Feet 74 letter document boxes
  - The Wolfsonian/ Florida International University Foundation, 20090193, 2009 June 8-2014 December 31 (Box 164, Folder 9)
    Grant 20090193, The Wolfsonian/ Florida International University Foundation, $500,000 to expand the reach of the museum by projecting images of the collection and new works on its exterior walls.
  - 100 Words Film Festival, LLC, 2014-49487, 2014 September 1-2015 January 31 (Box 165, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 5801
    Grant 2014-49487, 100 Words Film Festival, LLC, $20,400. To support the launch of the 100 Words Film Festival - an innovative and engaging short form film festival in Charlotte.
  - Akron Art Museum, 2013-42770, 2013 March 1-2016 April 1 (Box 165, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 5802
    Restricted - Open in 2027
    Grant 2013-42770, Akron Art Museum, $750,000. To support groundbreaking exhibitions at the Akron Art Museum as it transitions to new leadership and strives to become a model for small to mid-sized art museums.
  - Detroit Educational Television Foundation, 2014-49871, 2014 October 1-2015 September 30 (Box 165, Folder 8)
    Knight File Number - 5807
    Grant 2014-49871, Detroit Educational Television Foundation, $120,000. To raise Miami's profile as a hub for the literary arts and reach new audiences through an expansion of Detroit Public Television's national broadcast and live stream coverage of Miami Book Fair International.
  - Detroit Educational Television Foundation, 2015-51582, 2015 November 1-2016 August 29 (Box 165, Folder 9)
    Knight File Number - 5808
    Grant 2015-51582, Detroit Educational Television Foundation, $150,000. To raise Miami's profile as a hub for the literary arts and expand audience engagement with, and access to, Miami Book Fair International programs by supporting Detroit Public Television's coverage of the weeklong event on their national broadcast, digital and social media platforms.
  - Jorge M. Perez Art Museum, 2015-50805, 2015 May 1-2016 November 30 (Box 166, Folder 10)
    Knight File Number - 5818
    Grant 2015-50805, Jorge M. Perez Art Museum, $94,100. To support the launch of a pilot year of Inside\Out - an audience engagement initiative that will bring ornately framed high-quality reproductions of works from the collection of the Perez Art Museum Miami into neighborhoods throughout Miami-Dade County.
  - Miami-Dade College Foundation, Inc., 2015-51448, 2015 November 1-2016 October 31 (Box 167, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 5821
    Grant 2015-51448, Miami-Dade College Foundation, Inc., $50,000. To reach new audiences for the arts in northwest Miami Dade through support for a two week artist residency with the New York based Ladd Brothers at the Museum of Art+Design and "Scrollathon"-a workshop to demystify the meaning and practice of contemporary art for local schoolchildren by creating two murals comprised of each participant's story told through the assembly of recycled materials.
  - New Museum of Contemporary Art, 2014-49987, 2015 February 1-2016 January 31 (Box 168, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 5828
    Grant 2014-49987, New Museum of Contemporary Art, $150,000. To engage Detroit's artists and residents with IDEAS CITY: Detroit - a three day working lab and conference to take place November 2015, that will explore the future of Detroit through the lens of arts and culture.
  - Philadelphia Photo Arts Center, 2015-51436, 2015 November 1-2016 October 31 (Box 168, Folder 5)
    Knight File Number - 5832
    Grant 2015-51436, Philadelphia Photo Arts Center, $ 50,000. To engage audiences with a contemporary photography exhibition through a partnership with designer Hank Willis Thomas - a widely published and presented artist who will collect community generated images from the North Philadelphia neighborhood to create a life-scale model of a city block that will serve as a catalyst for discussion of geographic identity and neighborhood change.
  - Miami Music Project, 20080215, 2008 December 15-2013 July 31 (Box 170, Folder 1-2)
    Knight File Number - 5861
    Miami Music Project, 20080215, $1,000,000. To extend the joy of music to students in Miami-Dade schools through a year-round classical education program culminating in an annual festival with performances by youth and professional musicians
  - Taller Puertorriqueno, 20110071, 2011 April 1-2013 May 31 (Box 170, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 5860
    Taller Puertorriqueno, 20110071, $75,000. To provide a unique and alluring community setting where award-winning work is presented side-by-side with local and emerging talent in a series of seven monthly outdoor, live performances in the Heart of Latino Philadelphia
- Assessment and Impact, 2015-2016; 2; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - Media Impact Funders, Inc., 2015-51374, 2015 September 1-2016 July 31 (Box 167, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 5820
    Grant 2015-51374, Media Impact Funders, Inc., $25,000. To support Media Impact Funders in its efforts to strengthen practice and impact measurement among journalism and media funders.
- Communities Program, 2005-2015; 3; 9.49 Cubic Feet 25 letter document boxes
  - 1st ACT Silicon Valley, 20070154, 2007 October 1-2011 November 30 (Box 129, Folder 5)
    Knight File Number - 5001
    Grant 20070154, 1st ACT Silicon Valley, $3,515,000 to create a new sense of place in Silicon Valley by supporting an initiative that uses the lens of creativity to bring the future into focus and inspire physical and cultural improvements.
  - Catholic Charities Legal Services Archdiocese of Miami, Inc., 20100041, 2010 May 1-2011 April 30 (Box 130, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 5004
    Grant 2010041, Catholic Charities Legal Services Archdiocese of Miami, Inc., $100,000, to support earthquake relief efforts in Miami's Haitian community through direct legal counseling to Haitian individuals.
  - City Year, 20080022, 2008 March 10-2011 April 30 (Box 130, Folder 5)
    Knight File Number - 5007
    Grant 20080022, City Year, $1,200,000, to develop new young leaders while at the same time have an impact on education in Miami by supporting the start-up, launch and implementation of a full-time City Year site in Miami-Dade County.
  - College for Creative Studies, 20090114, 2009 October 1-2011 December 31 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 5008
    Grant 20090114, College for Creative Studies, $1,010,000, to provide a new anchor institution in the northernmost end of Detroit's proposed "Creative Corridor".
  - College for Creative Studies, 20090114 - Argonaut Project Short Video, 2006 July 21 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
  - I-Lead, Inc., 20080070, 2008 July 1-2011 July 31 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 5013
    Grant 20080070, I-Lead, Inc. $900,000 to improve Philadelphia's educational attainment rankings by creating a new delivery model for college education in distressed neighborhoods.
  - Jumpstart, Inc., 20050176, 2005 September 20-2011 October 31 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 5015
    Grant 20050176, Jumpstart, Inc., $1,500,000, to promote economic development and employment growth in Akron and Summit County by providing financial and human capital for promising startup companies.
  - Miami Art Museum of Dade County Association (now Jorge M. Perez Art Museum of Miami), 20090154, 2009 October 31-2009 October 31 (Box 133, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 5017
    Grant 20090154, Miami Art Museum of Dade County Association (now Jorge M. Perez Art Museum of Miami Dade County Inc.), $50,000 to support Miami Art Museum's executive search for a chief curator, a search necessary in ensuring the overall vitality of the institution.
  - Miami-Dade College Foundation, Inc., 20090085, 2009 September 1-2011 August 31 (Box 134, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 5020
    Grant 20090085, Miami-Dade College Foundation, Inc., $100,000 to enhance Miami's recognition as a platform for quality film programming by funding two $25,000 grand jury prize awards over two years to filmmakers in the Miami International Film Festival World and IberoAmerican competitions.
  - The Miami Herald Charities, Inc., 20100052, 2010 May 1-2011 April 30 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    Knight File Number - 5042
    Grant 20100052, The Miami Herald Charities, Inc., $75,000, to fund student scholarships for the 52nd Silver Knight Awards, a ceremony recognizing outstanding students who have not only maintained good grades but have also applied their knowledge to contribute significant service to their schools and communities.
  - The Saint Paul Foundation, 20080024, 2008 March 10-2011 April 30 (Box 137, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 5033
    Grant 20080024, The Saint Paul Foundation, $1,575,000, to support the transformation of St. Paul neighborhoods adjacent to a planned light rail line by fostering a unique collaboration of government, nonprofit andprovate stakeholders.
  - Sant La Haitian Neighborhood Center, 20100044, 2008 December 15-2011 December 31 (Box 138, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 5034
    Grant 20100044, Sant La Haitian Neighborhood Center, $250,000, to support earthquake relief efforts in Miami's Haitian community through three distinct initiatives: Community Support and Counseling, Census Outreach and Naturalization Outreach.
  - United Way of Miami-Dade, 20100048, 2010 May 1-2011 April 30 (Box 138, Folder 5)
    Knight File Number - 5038
    Grant 20100048, United Way of Miami-Dade, $100,000, to support earthquake relief efforts in Miami's Haitian community through basic needs and food bank assistance.
  - Boys and Girls Club of South Central Kansas Inc., 20070271, 2007 December 10-2012 December 31 (Box 140, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 5196
    Grant 20070271, Boys & Girls Club of South Central Kansas, Inc., $2,000,000 to address Wichita's talent imperative by creating an innovative program that networks youth development and workforce development in the setting of a key neighborhood institution.
  - Mercer University, 20090071, 2009 June 8-2012 November 30 (Box 144, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 5163
    Grant 20090071, Mercer University, $2,000,000, to revitalize Macon's historic neighborhoods and business districts through the establishment of the College Hill Alliance.
  - Opportunity Fund Northern California, 20080074, 2008 June 9-2012 July 31 (Box 145, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 5168
    Grant 20080074, Opportunity Fund Northern California, $1,855,000, to fund the Citizenship Savings Program (an Individual Development Account, IDA) to address the financial barriers associated with citizenship fees for immigrant populations in Silicon Valley.
  - United Way of the Midlands, 20080066, 2008 June 9-2012 July 31 (Box 147, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 5174
    Grant 20080066, United Way of the Midlands, $5,000,000 to launch a comprehensive housing and services program for the homeless to decrease homelessness in Columbia and address a persistent obstacle to downtown development.
  - University of Akron, 20060112, 2006 September 12-2012 October 31 (Box 148, Folder 1-2)
    Knight File Number - 5175
    Grant 20060112, University of Akron, $10,000,000 to support the core organization that proposes to develop University Park, revitalizing a community anchored by two key institutions and using innovative approaches to health and lifelong learning as part of the area's development theme. 2 folders
  - University of Akron, 20060112 - Draft Transportation and Traffic Study, 2008 September (Box 148, Folder 2)
  - Zero One (ZERO1) - The Art and Technology Network, 20090072, 2009 June 8-2012 August 31 (Box 149, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 5177
    Grant 20090072, Zero One (ZERO1) - The Art and Technology Network, $975,000, to build an internationally recognized cultural identity and sense of place for the Silicon Valley by strengthening ZERO1's organizational capacity and making its biennial international digital arts festival a signature cultural event.
  - Zero One (ZERO1) - The Art and Technology Network, 20090072 - 01SJ: A Global Festival of Art on the Edge, 2008 June 4-8 (Box 149, Folder 2)
  - Akron Area YMCA, 20100091, 2010 July 1-2013 June 30 (Box 150, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 5326
    Grant 20100091, Akron Area YMCA, $3,000,000 to help fund the construction of University Park YMCA, a new facility in Akron's biomedical corridor.
  - Area/Code Entertainment, 20100023, 2010 April 1-2013 December 31 (Box 150, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 5327
    Grant 20100023, Area/Code Entertainment, $492,590, to support the development and implementation of a game in Macon that uses an alternative form of local currency - Macon Money - to literally connect Macon residents to each other and to the College Hill Corridor in new ways.
  - Blue Grass Community Foundation, 20070263, 2007 December 10-2013 April 30 (Box 151, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 5330
    Grant 2007026, Blue Grass Community Foundation, $2,550,000, to use the 2010 World Equestrian Games, an Olympics-like event held for the first time in the U.S. as a springboard for capital and social improvements, creating an enduring legacy for the community.
  - Citizen Schools, Inc., 20080021, 2008 March 10-2013 July 31 (Box 151, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 5331
    Grant 20080021, Citizen Schools, Inc., $2,100,000, to increase citizen involvement in the public schools by expanding a successful after-school program while experimenting with emerging technology to strengthen the volunteers' role with the organization and its long-term future.
  - Friends of the Saint Paul Public Library, 20090204, 2009 December 7-2013 January 31 (Box 152, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 5336
    Grant 20090204, Friends of the Saint Paul Library, $300,000, to increase access to job search assistance and computer based job skill training outside of Library facilities, particularly for people who speak English as their secondary language.
  - Ivy Tech Community College Northwest, 20080186, 2008 December 8-2013 April 30 (Box 153, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 5339
    Grant 20080186, Ivy Tech Community College Northwest, $400,000, to support Dare to Dream: One Region, One Vision leadership development initiative across Gary, Ind., and seven surrounding counties, an unprecedented convening and training of leaders in this region.
  - Ivy Tech Community College Northwest, 20080186 - Unknown Soldiers: Stageplay DVD Performance (Box 153, Folder 2)
    The story of the challenges and opportunities facing our 7 counties of Northwest Indiana, written by Ben Clement, directed by Mark Spencer.
  - Ivy Tech Community College Northwest, 20080186 - The Spirit of Invitation...for a 7-County Conversation (Box 153, Folder 2)
  - Wichita State University Foundation, 20080124, 2008 September 15-2013 October 31 (Box 156, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 5351
    Grant 20080124, Wichita State University Foundation, $2,000,000, to transform the way students in south central Kansas learn science, technology, engineering and math by creating a comprehensive elementary through college education system that will be replicated throughout the state.
  - Alaska Community Foundation, 2013-46471, 2013 October 1-2014 October 31 (Box 159, Folder 7)
    Knight File Number - 5649
    Grant 2013-46471, Alaska Community Foundation, $50,000, to use a critical issue to launch intensive use of data journalism in Alaska.
  - Community Foundation of Central Georgia, 20090070, 2009 June 8-2014 June 30 (Box 160, Folder 7)
    Knight File Number - 5656
    Grant 20090070, Community Foundation of Central Georgia, $3,000,000, to establish the Knight Neighborhood Challenge.
  - Detroit Creative Corridor Center, 20120036, 2012 March 12-2015 April 30 (Box 161, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 5658
    Grant 20120036, Detroit Creative Corridor Center, $510,000, to support the growth of "Design in Detroit" a three-year initiative that will engage 10,000 Metro-Detroiters as leaders who champion 1,000 projects proposed by the local creative community.
  - Michigan Corps, 2013-43557, 2013 June 1-2015 June 30 (Box 162, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 5668
    Grant 2013-43557, Michigan Corps, $150,000, to mobilize hundreds of residents to fund and champion Detroit entrepreneurs.
  - National Urban Fellows, 2013-47013, 2013 September 1-2014 August 31 (Box 162, Folder 7)
    Knight File Number - 5672
    Grant 2013-47013, National Urban Fellows, $37,500, to develop minority and female leaders for the government and nonprofit sector through the sponsorship of a class of 2014 Fellow to be placed with the City of Philadelphia in the Managing Director's office.
  - The Oregon Community Foundation, 20120156, 2012 June 11-2015 July 31 (Box 163, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 5676
    Grant 20120156, The Oregon Community Foundation, $302,000, to create the Northwest News Cooperative, a news network linking and serving rural Oregon news organizations.
  - Student African American Brotherhood, 20120258, 2012 November 1-2015 April 30 (Box 164, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 5685
    Grant 20120258, Student African American Brotherhood, $205,000, to provide operating and business development support to the Student African American Brotherhood to ensure their ability to effectively engage thousands of black males in strengthening their communities.
  - University of Miami, 20110081, 2011 April 1-2014 October 15 (Box 164, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 5687
    Grant 20110081, University of Miami, $235,000, to create the Knight Fellows Program at the University of Miami Rosenstiel School of Marine and Atmospheric Science, allowing the school to increase its research proficiency by attracting an elite class of national and international Ph. D. scientists.
  - Young Involved Philadelphia, 20120310, 2012 November 5-2014 November 30 (Box 164, Folder 10)
    Knight File Number - 5693
    Grant 20120310, Young Involved Philadelphia, $40,000 to prepare 170 young professionals over the next two years for non-profit board service.
- Community and National Initiatives, 2009-2016; 4; 3.8 Cubic Feet 10 letter document boxes
  - Municipal Art Society of New York, 2013-47328, 2014 February 1-December 31 (Box 158, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 5505
    Grant 2013-47328, The Municipal Art Society of New York, $58,000 to expand the Jane's Walk program into Knight resident communities and develop a model and set of resources for expansion into other cities across the U.S.
  - Root Cause Institute, 20120257, 2012 November 1-2014 July 31 (Box 159, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 5507
    Grant 20120257, Root Cause Institute, $250,000, to launch and pilot the Leadership and Sustainability Institute which will help support and sustain at least 30 Knight grantees working in the Black Male Achievement field.
  - United Way for Southeastern Michigan, 20080120, 2009 September 1-2014 June 30 (Box 159, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 5509
    Grant 20080120, United Way for Southeastern Michigan, $1,025,000, to support a funders collaborative in the Detroit metro region that will develop critical workforce partnerships between employers, workforce development agencies, community-based organizations and the philanthropic community.
  - CCCP Community Trust, 2014-49577, 2014 October 1-2015 June 30 (Box 160, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 5653
    Grant 2014-49577, CCCP Community Trust, $125,000, to support core city vibrancy in Charlotte by using Gehl Architects' first techniques to develop new criteria for the planning of public spaces in Charlotte.
  - CultureWorks Greater Philadelphia, 2013-47211, 2014 February 1-2015 January 31 (Box 161, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 5657
    Grant 2013-47211, CultureWorks Greater Philadelphia, $30,000, to produce TEDxPhiladelphia 2014, a one-day conference highlighting Philadelphia's past, present and future as a hub for entrepreneurs, manufacturers and artists, and attracting and featuring the region's most innovative talent.
  - The New School, 2014-49974, 2014 December 1-2015 July 31 (Box 162, Folder 9)
    Knight File Number - 5674
    Grant 2014-49974, The New School, $107,652, to pilot the Urban Prototyping Lab, an IDEO bootcamp designed to test core project assumptions and prototype with two Knight Cities Challenge finalists.
  - 8-80 Cities, 2015-51367, 2015 September 1-2015 December 31 (Box 165, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 5800
    Grant 2015-51367, 8-80 Cities, $30,000, to encourage civic engagement in Knight Communities by documenting the 2015 Copenhagen Study Tour, covering the cost of additional delegates, and supporting 880s presentation at the 2015 Open Streets Summit.
  - Center for the Living City, 2014-48200, 2014 March 1-2015 February 28 (Box 165, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 5803
    Grant 2014-48200, Center for the Living City, $100,000. To publish and to publicize the English translation of Jaime Lerner's book Urban Acupuncture, to inspire cities to invest in meaningful, small-scale interventions that can spark community transformation.
  - The Committee of Seventy, 2016-52449, 2016 March 25-August 31 (Box 165, Folder 6)
    Knight File Number - 5805
    Grant 2016-52449, Committee of Seventy, The, $45,000. To educate young minority residents of Philadelphia on the importance of voting and nonpartisan civic engagement by supporting the Committee of Seventy's production of an interactive nonpartisan civic engagement performance, "Voices of Voting".
  - Gehl.Org, Inc., 2015-51897, 2015 December 1-2016 July 31 (Box 166, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 5810
    Grant 2015-51897, Gehl.Org, Inc., $ 198,800. To promote civic engagement by supporting a two-day conference of experts, innovators and instigators from Knight communities and others who are promoting and creating robust public life.
  - Girls Who Code, Inc., 20120343, 2012 December 10-2014 December 9 (Box 166, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 5811
    Grant 20120343, Girls Who Code, Inc., $435,000. To help address the shortage of women in the technology field by deploying a new program in Detroit, Miami, and San Jose to encourage girls (ages 13-17) to build their skills and seek opportunities in technology.
  - Global Detroit, 2014-49293, 2014 July 1-2015 January 31 (Box 166, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 5812
    Grant 2014-49293, Global Detroit, $60,000. To support and continue the development of the Global Great Lakes Network, a nascent network of regional immigration economic development initiatives across the Midwest - accelerating civic engagement and talent retention.
  - Institute for the Future, 2015-50922, 2015 June 1-2016 May 31 (Box 166, Folder 6)
    Knight File Number - 5814
    Grant 2015-50922, Institute for the Future, $250,000. To support Knight's understanding of talent retention and attraction by funding the Workable Futures Initiative that will track new emerging work patterns and contribute to the design of public policies that are in line with this new working economy.
  - Island Press, 2015-50309, 2015 January 1-July 31 (Box 166, Folder 7)
    Knight File Number - 5815
    Grant 2015-50309, Island Press, $74,650. To support the development and publication of Gabe Klein's "Getting Sh*t Done In Cities, "a book on proven strategies to build effective public-private partnerships that help cities succeed.